<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on greaysweater42&#39;s cookbook</title>
    <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on greaysweater42&#39;s cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:47:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://greysweater42.github.io/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA Serverless Lambda</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/nba-serverless-lambda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:47:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/nba-serverless-lambda/</guid>
      <description>Example of using serverless framework with Python link to the github repository
This simple project demonstrates how you can use serverless framework to run a simple python function in AWS Lambda.
The function downloads the scores of the NBA games from yesterday and saves them to s3 bucket.
How it works Creating lambda function in AWS from scratch is a little bit tedious. Fortunately there is a serverless framework software which facilitates it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>favourite pet?</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/favourite_pet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 22:07:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/favourite_pet/</guid>
      <description>1. What am I doing? I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find out if you can tell if a person is talking about their Python or dog, when the person does not use any of the words &amp;ldquo;python&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;dog&amp;rdquo;.
Apart from being funny for me, I want to practice creating and learning RNNs, LSTMs in particular.
2. Dataset is taken from reddit, because of its simple API. This time praw, which is an excellent python package for downloading any information/data from reddit was not enough, as it allows to get only 1000 posts at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reading mate</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/reading_mate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:32:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/reading_mate/</guid>
      <description>1. Is it OK to judge people by the books they read? Well, not really. Personally, from time to time I read complete crap purposedly, out of curiosity and to form my own opinion about it (I didn&amp;rsquo;t like 50 Shades of Gray as much as I had expected) and sometimes I read books which may seem completely contradictory to my views/beliefs, because I try to be open and give them a chance to convince me (which sometimes happens, but e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fiat 126 v ferrari</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/fiat_ferrari/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 16:40:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/fiat_ferrari/</guid>
      <description>1. Can you tell the difference between these two cars?    Me neither, but let&amp;rsquo;s see if a convolutional neural network can.
2. What am I doing? I am practicing my CNN skills on a subject that is particularly close to my heart: a legendary vehicle Fiat 126p in which I was travelling around Poland with my family in the 1990s. To me this was the best car in the world and it left many cars behind in various categories, mainly styling and&amp;hellip; well, styling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neural networks vs stock market</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/finance_nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:17:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/finance_nn/</guid>
      <description>1. Intro 1. Why I’m making this project There are two main reasons for this project:
 I’ve recently deep dived into pytorch and I want to test in on a real task. I’ve been using pytorch extensively at work, but I usually didn’t have enough time to study its quirks as thouroughly as I wanted.
 As I was studying Quantitative Methods in Economy, my all-time dream was to predict fluctuations on the stock market, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>writing a cookbook</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 17:58:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/cookbook/</guid>
      <description>1. Why writing a cookbook/blog? In 2016, when I decided to become a data scientist, I was overwhelmed by the number of skills I had to possess to start this sort of career. Reading job offers convinced me that I should be a specialist in:
  statistics and mathematics (which I learned at the univerity),
  machine learning and data mining (which are fairly easy to learn by yourself if you have a statistical background),</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim vs emacs - text mining to settle the editor war</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/vim_vs_emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 14:12:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/vim_vs_emacs/</guid>
      <description>This project is not finished and will be developed over time.
 0. Why I’m making this project  I want to try out new programming and statistical tools that I read or heard about (tidytext, nlp, laser) on a subject that I find interesting (text editors).
 If somebody asks me if vim is a good choice for a text editor, I want to have objective arguments to prove my statement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>