<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on greaysweater42&#39;s cookbook</title>
    <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on greaysweater42&#39;s cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 16:22:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://greysweater42.github.io/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>sqlAlchemy</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/sqlalchemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 16:22:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/sqlalchemy/</guid>
      <description>1. What is sqlAlchemy and why would you use it?   sqlAlchemy is a python module that enables you to connect to and use sql databases without writing code in sql;
  using sqlAlchemy has several advantages:
  you will avoid using long sql strings in your code, which are difficult to read without syntax highlighting (unless you keep you sql queries in separate sql files);
  you are not vulnerable to sql injection attacks anymore;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RMariaDB (former RMySQL)</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/rmariadb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 12:17:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/rmariadb/</guid>
      <description>1. What is RMariaDB and why would you use it?  RMariaDB is an R package available at CRAN that let’s you connect to various SQL databases easily.  Why did I switch from RMySQL to RMariaDB? Because of invalid long integer format when downloading data from a database. A pretty nasty bug in RMySQL, which was resolved in RMariaDB.
 2. Usage First you have to create a connection to the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sqldf</title>
      <link>https://greysweater42.github.io/sqldf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 13:07:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greysweater42.github.io/sqldf/</guid>
      <description>1. What is sqldf and why would you use it? sqldf package lets you treat any data.frame object as an sql table, which means that you can write queries just as if you were using an sql database. Since the emergence of libraries such as data.table or dplyr + tidyverse, sqldf turns out to be fairly useless, so now it is rather a curiosity than a game-changer.
Despite its uselessness, it works like a charm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>